Module 2.0 environments in which projects
operate module overview.
In this module we will cover
2.0 environments in which
projects operate module
overview, which is this video.
2.1 Enterprise Environmental Factors,
2.2 organizational process assets and 2.
3 organizational systems.
environments in which projects operate,
the Pimbaughan says that projects exist
and operate in environments that may have
an influence on them.
These influences can have a favourable or
a non-favorable impact on the project.
Two major categories of influences are
enterprise environmental factors,
EEFs and organisational process assets,
OPS.
enterprise environmental factors originate
from the environment outside the project
and despite the name enterprise they can
often be from outside the enterprise as
well enterprise environmental factors may
have an impact on the organization
portfolio program or project level
organizational process assets are internal
to the organization These may arise from
the organisation itself, a portfolio,
a programme, another project, or a
combination of these.
Figure 2.1 shows the breakdown
of project influences into
enterprise environmental factors
and organisational process assets.
In addition to enterprise environmental
factors and organisational process assets,
organisational systems play a significant
role in the large.
lifecycle of the project.
System factors that impact the power,
influence, interests, competencies and
political capabilities of the people to
act within the organizational system are
discussed further in the section on
organizational system.
And that brings us to
the end of a very short
environment in which projects
operate module overview.
The next lesson is 2.1 enterprise
environmental factors.
Please read the corresponding chapter.
in the Pimbaugh guide before watching the
video.